Finding aid to the Alexander C. Sanger papers SSC.MS.00654
Sophia Smith Collection
Alexander C. Sanger papers
1955-2017
Sophia Smith Collection
Sanger, Alexander Campbell, 1947-
SSC.MS.00654
46.542 linear feet (104 containers)
The Alexander C. Sanger papers document Alexander Sanger's work as President and CEO of Planned Parenthood of New York City, and his involvement in Planned Parenthood Federation of America, the International Planned Parenthood Federation, and the general struggle for reproductive rights in the U.S. and abroad. The collection also includes materials related to the Virginia B. Toulmin Foundation Program for Commissioning Women in the Performing Arts, founded by Alexander Sanger in 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use with following restrictions on access: The Virginia B. Toulmin Foundation materials, located in boxes 96, 97, and 98, are restricted until 2034.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were gifted to the Smith College Special Collections by Alexander C. Sanger between 2009 and 2017.
Biographical Note
Alexander C. Sanger is an American reproductive rights activist and, as of 2019, the current chair of the International Planned Parenthood Council. He is the grandson of Margaret Sanger, the founder of Planned Parenthood. He was born November 25, 1947 in New York City, the fourth child (of six) of Grant and Edwina Campbell Sanger. He was raised in Mt. Kisco, New York and attended the Bedford Rippowam School until eighth grade and then Phillips Academy in Andover, Massachusetts, followed by Princeton University, where he wrote his senior thesis on his grandmother, Margaret Sanger. He remembers being, in 1968, the first researcher in his grandmother's archives at Smith College. Archivists, led by Margaret Grierson, were still unpacking and cataloguing cartons of Margaret Sanger's letters, speeches and other documents.
Sanger is the author of Beyond Choice: Reproductive Freedom in the 21st Century (2004). Sanger is Chair of the International Planned Parenthood Council and has served as a Goodwill Ambassador for the United Nations Population Fund. He previously served as the President of Planned Parenthood of New York City (PPNYC) and its international arm, The Margaret Sanger Center International (MSCI) for ten years from 1991 - 2000. As president of PPNYC during the 1990's, Sanger led the agency in many political and social triumphs. In May 1991, he and PPNYC's Board of directors decided to reject federal funding tied to the Gag Rule that would have prohibited its medical professionals from mentioning abortion when counseling patients. Shortly after assuming the Presidency of PPNYC, Sanger launched the Clinician Training Initiative, designed to address the disturbing fact that few doctors were trained or willing to perform abortions. Since its inception in 1993, the program has trained over 100 Ob-Gyn residents and has accomplished two major policy victories with lasting national impact. In response to PPNYC's recommendation, the Accreditation Council of Graduate Medical Education began requiring all Ob-Gyn residents to be trained in performing abortions. PPNYC also persuaded New York State officials to allow physician assistants to perform abortions. Sanger established PPNYC as a leader in medical abortion. PPNYC was the first to offer medical abortions using methotrexate to patients, and sponsored a national conference in May 1997 to educate the medical community about the merits, methods and concerns of medical abortions, preparing the way for providers to add RU-486 to their services. Under Sanger's stewardship, PPNYC acted as a vigilant watchdog over local, state and federal policies affecting women's reproductive health. Due to PPNYC's 1995 petition, the FDA announced in February of 1997 that birth control pills could be used safely and effectively as an emergency contraceptive. And when federal restrictions were established prohibiting the dispersal of abortion information on the Internet, Sanger brought suit (Sanger v. Reno), against the government to enjoin the law's enforcement of The Communications Decency Act of 1996.
As a spokesperson and advocate, Sanger was named One of the 100 Most Influential People on the Planet in 1995 by Earth Times. He attended and lectured at both the 1994 United Nations International Conference on Population and Development in Cairo and The United Nations Fourth World Conference on Women at Beijing in 1995. Sanger directed extensive lobbying efforts to convince members of Congress to unlock international family planning funds in early 1997 and each year thereafter. He is committed to raising awareness in America and throughout the world about the need and demand in developing countries for quality reproductive health care, education and facilities. Sanger's background also includes six years as a partner in the law firm of White and Case and three years running a manufacturing business. In addition to his BA in history from Princeton, he holds a doctor of jurisprudence and master of business administration degrees from Columbia University, and a master of laws from New York University.
Related Materials
Margaret Sanger papers, Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records
Scope and Contents
The collection is primarily made up of files documenting Sanger's work as President and CEO of Planned Parenthood of New York City, and his involvement in Planned Parenthood Federation of America, the International Planned Parenthood Federation, and the general struggle for reproductive rights in the U.S. and abroad. Materials include correspondence, Board of Director's files, speeches, photographs, audiovisual materials, reports, surveys, publicity materials, and press releases. The collection also includes materials related to the Virginia B. Toulmin Foundation Program for Commissioning Women in the Performing Arts, founded by Alexander Sanger in 2013, including trustee meeting minutes, correspondence, and grant applications.
Abortion -- Law and legislation -- United States -- History -- Sources; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government; Population policy -- History; Reproductive rights -- United States -- History -- Sources; Public health -- United States -- History; International Planned Parenthood Federation -- History -- Sources; Planned Parenthood of New York City -- History -- Sources; Agendas; Audiotapes; Book; Buttons; Calendars; CD-Roms; Computer media; Minutes; Surveys; Videotapes; Abortion--Law and legislation-United States--History--Sources; Planned Parenthood Federation of America--History--Sources; Birth control--Developing countries--History--Sources; press releases; Philanthropists--United States--History--Sources; Birth control clinics--United States--History--Sources; Birth control--United States--History--Sources; New York (N.Y.)--Politics and government; Women's health services--United States; Women in the performing arts--History--Sources; Reproductive health--Statistics; Abortion services--History--Sources; articles; Annual reports; Publicity; Writings; Photographs.; Speeches.; correspondence; reports; clippings; Sanger, Alexander C.; Virginia B. Toulmin Foundation Program for Commissioning Women in the Performing Arts; Sanger, Margaret, 1879-1966; International Planned Parenthood Federation; Planned Parenthood Federation of America; Planned Parenthood of New York City; Sanger, Alexander C.
- Biographical material, 1955-2016; 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains A.S.'s senior thesis, Sanger Center guest book, self-portrait, clippings, awards, memoir, W. Sanger house drawing and watercolors, Bar applications, and articles.
  - General, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Senior Thesis, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Margaret Sanger Center Guest Book, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers and Clippings, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alexander C. Sanger self portrait, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Awards Received, 1991-2008 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Book / Inscriptions made out to Alexander C. Sanger, 1955, 1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Edward Sanger memoir, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - William Sanger, house drawing, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Article on Jeanette Watson Sanger, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alexander Sanger Bar applications, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Tour Schedule and Itineraries, 2004-2005 (Box 99)
  - Andover Auction, October 2011 (Box 99)
  - The Sangers - Rebels and Artists, April - May, 2015 (Box 99)
  - Island Journal - Map, 2015 (Box 99)
  - PPMHV Sanger - Art show, April 21, 2016 (Box 99)
  - William Sanger - Downeast - Watercolors by William Sanger, 2016 May 13 - June 12 (Box 99)
- Correspondence, 1966-2011; 2
  This series includes correspondence from notable individuals, chronological correspondence, and IPPR/WHR correspondence.
  Arrangement
  A portion of this series has been arranged chronologically and the 'notable individuals correspondence' has been arranged alphabetically.
  - Individuals, incoming, 1970-2007; A (Box 2, Box 3)
    - Gary Ackerman (NY-5), 1996 December 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Jean Carnahan, 2002 December 23 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Ellen Chester, 1987-2004 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Childesign, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - City of New York, 1989-2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - City of New York, Governor's Office, 1991-2005 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bill Clinton, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Joan Coombs, 1991-2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - May Del Rio, 1995-2007 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Eliot L. Engel (NY-19), 1991, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Madelaine Gray, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Al Gore, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Porter Goss (FL-14), 2002-2005 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Katherine Hepburn, 1989-1996, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - International Center for Photography, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Internatonal Planned Parenthood Federation, 2000-2006 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Robin Fins-Kaplan, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Taki Kato-Kurokawa, 1997-2001 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - John Kerry, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Ed Koch, 1991-1996 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Princeton University, 1994-2008 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Peter Purdy, 1989, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Miriam Reed, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Bill Richardson, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Roberta Schniederman, 1993-1997 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Patricia Schroeder (CO-1), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Chuck Schumer (NY Senator), 1999 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Senator Thank You Notes for copy of Beyond Choice, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Sophia Smith Collection, 1969-1998 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - State of New York, 1991-2004 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - State of New York Governor's Office, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Anna Sussman, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Lionel Tiger, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Edolphus Towns, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Philip F. Trego, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - United Nations, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - United Nations Population Fund, 2000-2005 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Nydia M. Velazquez (NY-12), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Faye Wattleton, 1981-2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Nancy Whitelaw, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - John Wolfe, 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Michelle Woodruff, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Outgoing (chronological), 1979-2009 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Third Party, 1990-2000 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Incoming, chronological, 1966-2011; B (Box 3, Box 4, Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 2000 January-August (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 2000 September-December (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 2001 January-June (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 2001 July-December (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 2002 January-May (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 2002 June-December (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 2003 January-July (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 2003 August-December (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - IPPR/WHR Correspondence, 2011-2016 (Box 99)
  - General Correspondence, 1993-2016 (Box 99)
- Speeches, 1959-2016; 3
  This series contains speeches given to numerous conferences and organizations, including to Planned Parenthood organizations around the country, colleges, hospitals, and churches, as well as correspondence related to speaking engagements.
  - Correspondence related to speaking engagements, A
    - Correspondence with All Souls Church, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with Congregants, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with Louis P. Postman, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "Should you leave it all to the children", 1987 May 11; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Interview with ABC, 1997; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Misc, 1994-1998, 2001, 2002; 6 folders (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 12, 13, 14, 15, 19, 26, 35)
    - Virginia League for Planned Parenthood 58th annual meeting, 1998 May 26; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Women's Campaign Fund Annual Gala, 1998 October 19; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - PP of Metropolin NJ, 1998 March 10; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Chautauqua Institute, 2001 July 17; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - PP Development Officer's retreat, 2001 August 9; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - PPLA South Bay Friends/20th Anniversary, 2001 September 12-13; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - PP of Chester County PA, 2001 October 3-4; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - PP of Central PA 66th annual meeting, 2001 October 24; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - PP of Southeast MI Capital Campaign, 2001 October 25; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - PP of South Carolina, 2002 January 23-24; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - PP MET fundraiser, 2002 May 2; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - PP of Greater Iowa annual dinner, 2002 May 11; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - PP of CT annual celebration, 2002 May 16; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - PP of Mahoning Valley annual dinner, 2002 May 20; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - PP of Greater Cleveland spring forum, 2002 May 22; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - SFPA Nat'l Conference, 2002 June 17-18; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - PP Orlando, 2002 September 19; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - PP Rochester/Syracuse, 2003 June 5; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Central Region, PP NOVA, PP of Louisville, 2003 September 12-13; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Sophia Smith Collection PPLMA, 2003 September 15; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Westminster School, 2003 December 9; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Misc, 2003; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - SUNY New Paltz reproductive law and policy class, 2010 Fall; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Thank-you letters, 1995-2002; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Forrest Church Notes & Speech Versions, 1991 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Articles for Forrest Church Speech, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Garrison Forest School ACS Address, 1994 June 8; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - PPFA pamphlet with remarks by Gloria Feldt, 1997 July 17; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - PP of Golden Gate gala dinner, 2001 May 10; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Chautauqua Institution, 2001 July 17; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - PP of Central Pennsylvania and Development Officers Council, 2001 August; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - PP of Los Angeles, 2001 September 12, 13; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - PP of Chester County promotional materials, 2001 October 3; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - PP of Southeast Michigan dinner with ACS, 2001 October 25; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 5th North TX UN Conference on Women, 2001 November 3; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - SFPA National Conference, 2002 June 17-18; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - PP of Rochester/Syracuse annual report, 2003 May 27; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - IPPF, Western Hemisphere Region Events, 2002; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - PP of SC materials, 2002 January 24; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - PP of SW and Central Florida event material, 2002; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - NYC PP President Lecture at Princeton, 2002 April 19; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - IPPF 50th Anniversary Event, 2002 April 18; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - PP of Middle and East TN invitational clergy breakfast and Gala in the Gardens, 2002; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - PP of Iowa, 2002 May 11; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - PP of CT celebration, 2002 May 16; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - PP of Greater Cleveland and PP of Mahoning Valley dinner, 2002 May 20-22; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - PP of Greater Ontario fall luncheon, 2003; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Regional conference agendas and material, 2003 Sept-Oct; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - IPPF/WHR event materials, 2003 November 17; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Planned Parenthood events, 2005 May; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Invitation to IPPF events, 2009-2011; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - PP history- speech materials, 1959 March; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - PP NYC historical info- speech material, 1973-1979; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - PP NYC financial history- speech material, 1975-1985; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - PP NYC history- speech material, 1988-1989; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - ACS Notes, 1991; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - PP NYC history- speech materials, 1992; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Speech materials- notes, 1994; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - PP NYC historical info- speech materials, 1997; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Development Officers Council, Philadelphia, 2001 August 9; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Misc travel info for events, 2001; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Travel itineraries and contracts, 2002-2003; 1 folders (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 7, 8)
  - "Objectives of Good Estate Planning", 1974 November 27; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Commencement speeches, 1991-1994; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Margaret Sanger's 100th birthday anniversary, Rockland Planned Parenthood, 1979; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Nat'l Women's Hall of Fame, 1981; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - PP Tuscon, 1991 September 19; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Smith College, 1991 October 1; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Good Day New York, 1991 October 11; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - "Stand up for your rights," PP NYC, 1991 October 7; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - PP Palm Beach, 1991 November 7; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Bard College, 1991 November 18; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous speeches, 1991; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Speech notes, 1991; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Revision Fellows, 1992 February 4; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - PP Canton, OH, 1992 April 21; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - PP Columbia/Willamette, 1992 May 27; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Bleeker dedication speech, 1992 June 10; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - PP of Central Indiana, 1992 June 11; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Speech at rally, 1992 July 7; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Public affairs open house, 1992 September 10; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - PP Niagara County, 1992 September 30; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 10th Anniversary Open House Bronx, 1992 October 16; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Rotary Club, Kalamazoo, Michigan, 1992 October 26; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Statement 10, Transportation Committee, 1992 December 8; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous speeches and notes, 1992; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - PP Houston, 1993 February 4; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Women's City Club, 1993 March 11; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Lincoln Center, NYC, 1993 April; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - PP of the Souther Tier, 1993 May 14; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - PP Cleveland, 1993 May 19; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - PP Broome and Chenango, 1993 June 23; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Ravitz Town Hall speech, 1993 September 30; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Margaret Sanger Sq. block party, 1993 September 8; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - PP Santa Barbara, 1993 November 1; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Alfred Ross introduction, 1993 November 17; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Speech notes, 1993; 2 folders (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 21, 22)
  - FPA Annual Legislative Conference, 1994 January 23; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - PP NE Pennsylvania, 1994 March 13; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Presentation to the UN ICPD, 1994 April 7; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - PP NNE, 1994 May 25; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "Norplant, what's all the fuss about?", 1994 June 30; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Testimony to the Governor's Commission for the Study of Youth Crime and Violence, 1994 September 21; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Bucks County, 1994 November 4; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1994 December 1; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Press briefing with JAMWA, 1994 December 8; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - PP Nassau County, 1994 December 13; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - PP NYC Eulogies, 1994; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Misc speeches, 1994; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - PP Massachusetts, 1995 April 5; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Connecticut College, 1995 May 1; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Milwaukee, 1995 May 10; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Mercer Area, 1995 May 18; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - PP Northern New England, 1995 May 24; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Mohawk Valley, NY, 1995 June 1; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Testimony for the Joint Public Hearing on the expansion of Medicade managed care in NYC, 1995 July 27; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - PP Los Angeles, 1995 September 18; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - St Paul, MN, 1995 September 21; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - PP Jacksonville, FL, 1995 September 27; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - "Female genital mutilation: what is it and what can we do about it?", 1995 October 2; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 10, Folder 23)